Christopher Ashby

Global Security Leader | Board Member | Strategic Transformation Executive

(518) 577-8597

ashbyc@mac.com

https://ashbyca.com

PGP: 3679D138AE307F2A

Summary

Highly experienced pragmatic executive, trusted advisor, and strategic problem solver taking a collaborative approach on resolving complex security problems that enable businesses to achieve their outcomes successfully across all levels of the organization.

Demonstrated success architecting, improving, and managing global cyber security related programs with a constant willingness to align and respond to the evolving threat landscape, business needs, and regulatory requirements. Confident in leading diverse teams dedicated to assessing business risks, defining appropriate mitigation, managing enterprise execution, and enhancing operational efficiency.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Head of Cybersecurity Engineering and Innovation

Fresenius Medical Care, Waltham, MA, 2022-Present

Collaborated across leadership teams with direct accountability to build and oversee the cybersecurity strategy, vision, and roadmaps with a relentless focus on balancing security with simplification.

- Responsible for the development and execution in delivering nextgeneration cyber security capabilities across the enterprise.
- Role modeled. mentored, and promoted a culture of engineering excellence to strengthen the technical expertise and know-how of our cyber engineering teams.

Senior Cyber Security Engineer, Global Security Solutions

Alexion Pharmaceuticals, New Haven, CT, 2019–2022

Created and executed a comprehensive incident response, threat hunting, purple team, and hygiene cyber security program(s) across the organization. Acted as a threat reduction subject matter expert in various leadership working groups to continuously drive down risk and increase resiliency across the organization.

- Collaboratively worked across the enterprise to resolve identified issues including architecture, software, and hardware weaknesses.
- Worked closely with executives on mitigation strategies to ensure the appropriate levels of risk were maintained.
- Implemented continuous process improvements for cybersecurity incident response tactics, techniques, procedures.
- Served as a role model, teacher, mentor for security analysts, and IT workforce who weren't well versed in cyber risk or security operations.

SKILLS

Security Architecture

Adversarial Emulation

Policy and Governance

Project Management

Creative Thinking

Attack Surface Management

Security Program Metrics

Cyber Threat Intelligence

Security Orchestration and Automation

Employee Training and Development

Stakeholder Engagement

Cyber Risk Management

Posture Management

Education

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

Executive Education 2022-2022 Chief Information Security Officer (CISO) Certificate

Harvard, Cambridge MA

Graduate Certificate 2020-2020 Cyber Risk Management in the Information Age

Ithaca College, Ithaca NY

Graduate Certificate 2020-2020 Cyber Security Leadership

Cyber Intel Watch Commander

Digitalware, New York, NY, 2019-2019

Responsibilities included developing the long-term strategy and executing day to day management of a 24x7 Fusion Center environment which included a multifaceted elite team of technology engineers, data scientists, security analysts, and threat researchers serving multiple clients across various verticals including banking, entertainment, and local state governments.

- Conducted daily strategic threat briefings for high profile customers that included in-depth threat-actor assessments, TTPs, and risk reduction remediations.
- Executive level interactions in supporting city agencies C-suite particularly CISO, CSO, CIO, and CTO.

Director, Information Security

CBS Corporation, New York, NY, 2013–2018

Developed and managed the global threat intelligence strategy providing visibility around enabling a holistic view of the security threat landscape across the enterprise. Managed and automated the collection of OSINT & Commercial threat feeds producing operational intelligence for remote team consumption.

- Generated and delivered routine business readiness intelligence providing an early warning of potential threats
- Created and distributed threat metrics, advisories, and daily threat briefings that clearly articulated the security landscape to executives.

Principle IT Security Analyst

GLOBALFOUNDRIES, Malta, NY, 2011-2013

Work as a team lead responsible for US security operations within a global semiconductor manufacturing facility. General responsibilities included security operations, engineering, and security solutions design as necessary to support a mission critical global operation.

- Provided technical leadership to the enterprise for the information security programs and team members.
- Maintained, managed, and frequently engaged with third-party relationships.
- Recommended, implemented, and maintained, new and existing security infrastructure including network IPS devices, Firewalls, Proxies, and VPN appliances.
- Continuously assessed threats, risks, and vulnerabilities from emerging security events using various organic and vendor implemented solutions.

Information Security Specialist

The Active Network, Saratoga, NY, 2010-2011

Worked as a cyber security subject matter expert providing support and leadership on various company initiatives including:

- PCI compliance testing for Level1 Merchant Accreditation
- Network Security architecture reviews and audits
- Vulnerability discovery and Penetration testing

Certifications

Certified Risk Information Systems Control - CRISC

Certified Information Systems Security Professional - CISSP

Certified Cloud Security Professional - CCSP

Certified Information Security Manager - CISM

Publications

PenTest Regular Magazine Pass-The-Hash Attacks Published April 2013

Article explaining the post exploitation attack techniques used to elevate privileges and/or create new authenticated sessions.

PenTest Extra Magazine Automating Malware Analysis with Cuckoo Published: August 2013

Article on implementing an automated technique to aid in the identification and analysis of suspicious software.

PenTest Regular Magazine Extending Cuckoo Framework Published: November 2013

Article describing some of the advanced features, capabilities, and extensibility of the Cuckoo Platform.

Professional Associations

Ithaca College Board Member

InfraGard Southern CT Member

Operations Security Trust Member

ISC - Southern CT Chapter Member